In this video, we are going to talk about UV processing techniques.
First, let's talk about what is UV2.
UV2 can be simply understood as the picture formed by a 3D model of the surface texture to the 2D square area.
We can take a look at the model of the earth and the UV picture.
After the surface of a sphere is flattened into a square, it looks like this.
This is the UV picture of the sphere.
If we want the texture of the map to appear on this sphere,
then we have to place the map in the corresponding position to the sphere in the UV picture.
And after this UV picture is wrapped on our 3D sphere model,
the texture of the map will appear.
When we finish 3D clothing and want to import it into other 3D software,
we need to process its UV to ensure that the surface of the fabric is clean.
Then we can import it into other software.
Next, let's open the UV editor mode through the upper right corner.
Because 3D clothing is made up of 2D flat panels,
the UV picture of 3D clothing is the 3D version of the 3D clothing.
We can manually drag and drop to adjust the position of the panels.
Let's do the arrangement of the panels and the UV picture.
In the tool bar on the right side, there are also a series of UV tools.
Click on the automatic UV fill.
It will open a window.
Here.
Let's talk about the first concept.
UV area.
For better compatibility between different software.
It is generally recommended that the UV picture is placed in the default area 01,
which is our first line,
in the first unit grid.
Let's click on the application.
You can see that the UV of the panel will be displayed in the first unit grid.
Next, let's talk about some options in the UV layout.
First of all, the first one is fill.
It controls the gap between each panel UV.
Its data is set from 0.999 to 0.001.
The larger the data, the larger the gap between the panels.
For example, I changed it to 0.050 here.
You can see that there will be obvious gaps between the panels.
Here it is still changed to 0.001.
Next, look at the accuracy.
Here the maximum value is 5 and the minimum value is 1.
In the default situation, in order to ensure the accuracy of the UV layout,
and more reasonably use the space of the UV line,
there is a suitable calculation speed.
Set it to 3.
But when the number of panels is too large,
and the layout speed is slow,
you can reduce some accuracy
to quickly generate a layout result.
Next, let's look at the following options.
The first one is the fixed ratio.
The relative size of the panel is default to be the same as the 2D panel.
And when we cancel the fixed ratio,
you can see that some panels will be enlarged or reduced
for the space utilization rate of the layout.
This will lead to the final 3D model.
The clarity of the texture between different panels will be a little different.
So we usually choose the fixed ratio.
Now we can reset the layout of the UV,
and then select our fixed ratio.
Next is the rotation.
After selecting the rotation, click on the application.
You can see that in order to increase the utilization rate of this space,
it will rotate the entire panel.
Next is the optimization layout.
The optimization layout will be calculated in a more advanced way.
To layout our UV,
it will increase the utilization rate of the space.
In other words,
it will ensure that the UV is in the designated area,
and at the same time,
the panel will be enlarged as much as possible.
This will make our final fabric texture as clear as possible.
But on the contrary,
the calculation time it uses will be longer.
Then let's take a look at the UV quick photo tool.
It can save this current UV picture directly.
Next is the renovation pattern.
It can follow the current UV that is not good,
and its corresponding pattern,
hair line picture,
simulation picture,
transparent picture,
and other different material pictures,
are prepared and saved together.
Next is the UV movement.
We can select the important moving panel,
then click UV movement,
you can adjust the overall position of our panel.
You can enter its moving distance at the bottom.
Now it is moving a unit.
I modify it to 0.5 units.
At this time,
0.5 units are moved.
This tool is generally used to adjust the position of the overall UV picture.
After we have processed the UV picture of 3D clothing,
we can export it directly through the file,
and then export it to other 3D graphics.
In this process,
it will also export our UV picture.
For example,
we export OBZ,
after choosing,
it will open this window.
We can choose to export the thick one.
If it is thin,
the thickness of the fabric will not be exported.
So here we come to choose the thick one,
and also export the thickness of our fabric.
Next,
we can select the unified UV coordinates.
So it will export the UV information of our 3D clothing
and the UV picture together.
To make sure its texture can be exported normally,
let's take a look at the options.
First of all,
the first option is the size of the picture.
It can control the size of our UV picture.
Generally,
the larger the size of the image,
the clearer the picture will be,
but the size of the corresponding model will be larger.
Then the following is the fill texture.
The default is 5 pixels.
What's the use of this?
We can take a look at this example below.
Let's import an OBZ.
This OBZ
does not set the fill pixel.
In other words,
it does not have the advantage of that UV.
Then we can see that
it will appear in the place where the line is drawn.
The texture is not completely covered,
including the edge of the panel.
There is also this phenomenon.
This is its UV picture.
Then we can look at the UV picture of its line drawing.
The panel we export is a thick panel.
But according to the concept of our UV just now,
you should be able to understand that
this line drawing
has a thicker UV picture.
This way,
we can ensure that the whole line drawing
has a texture texture
so that it can have a texture package.
Therefore,
it needs a fill pixel here.
That is to say,
its UV pixel edge
has to have a certain protrusion.
In this way,
we can ensure that
the whole model
has a texture package.
Then below,
let's import an OBZ.
This OBZ
is the fill texture of 5 pixels.
Then you can see that
after the fill texture is performed,
the line drawing will become normal.
But
we will find that
some black edges
will appear in the pocket
and the waist part.
And this black edge
is because
our UV picture
is too close.
This is the UV picture
of the second model.
You can see that
after selecting the fill pixel,
its pixel edge will appear.
Then our drawstring
can be covered by the finished texture.
But it also appears
in a collision
with other panels,
so there will be
a partial black edge phenomenon.
Therefore,
for some of these panels,
the 3D model
will be thicker.
So when we are doing
UV arrangement,
we should pay attention
to a gap
between the panels.
For example,
if we want to
fill the space
between the panels,
we can use
the UV arrangement tool.
Then here,
we can input 0.005
where we fill the space.
In this way,
there will be a little more
gap between our panels.
We can see that
now there is a gap
between the panels.
Obviously,
there are more gaps.
Then the gap
between our drawstring panels
has also become larger.
At this time,
it will count the pixel fill
and it will not affect
our drawstring panels.
Then
we will
make this OBZ
one-touch.
The same choice is for the thick one.
Then
the pixel is filled
with five pixels.
Click OK.
Then
let's open
the OBZ we just made.
Here
we can see
that its drawstring
is normally displayed.
Moreover,
there is no
a situation
of covering each other
between UVs.
This is its UV picture.
We can see
that
there is no
covering
between each UV.
This is the content
of our UV processing techniques.
Thank you for watching.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community